JOBANPREET SINGH

UI DEVELOPER

CONTACT +91 91761 76607 singh.jobanpreet1992@gmail.com https://www.npmjs.com/~iamjoban https://github.com/iamjoban Bengaluru, India SKILLS HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript React, Redux Node Js Webpack Jest, Enzyme, RTL Appdynamic, Newrelic GraphQL Kafka Optimizely **JIRA** Git

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Applications

Punjabi University Patiala

2009 - 2012

PROFILE

I am a frontend developer with 10 years of experience in UI development and helping companies create and maintain a better code base for reusability. Capable of continuous learning from senior developers while still nurturing junior developers. Experience in driving projects forward as the development team leader, facilitating projects from concept to launch. Passionate about learning and development with a desire to apply skills on a larger development team. Eager to tackle more complex problems and continue to find ways to maximise user efficiency.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Engineer

Publicis Sapient

August 2018 - Present

esco

<u>Tesco Groceries</u> is an e-commerce website operated by Tesco. It offers a wide range of other products, including electronic goods, books, and financial services.

Contributions:

- · Leading a team of 5 engineers.
- Gathering requirements from Product owners. Being part of discovery meetings and talking to real customers.
- Migration to Micro Frontends.
- Cross-team communication to resolve dependency.
- UI development using React, Redux, SSR support using Node js and code reviews
- Provided solution for handling react rendering error on the server (https://www.npmjs.com/package/react-error-boundarywith-ssr-support)
- Reduced overall engineering cost of implementing and deploying A/B tests.
- Provided a solution to measure the performance of UI components.
- Features development including unit testing Code Review, deployment & support

Software Engineer

Xoriant solutions pvt ltd

November 2016 - August 2018

<u>Arbitrage Desktop Support</u>

The ADS has engines like classification engine which classifies customers and routes, flow-casting engine which prepares flow for sales offers, pricing engine forecasts price, Routing Engine monitor's default routes and negative routes and suggests alternate routes with shortest path algorithm and forecasting engine. All these engines are designed as different. Micro services and collaborations with each other. Any variation in factors affecting these routes like cost, quality etc.

Contributions:

- UI development using React .
- Implemented SPA using React Router.
- · Application data flow using Redux.
- Implemented user notification using Kafka.
- Production code bundling using Webpack.
- Implemented Node server to host UI and handle HTTP request coming from UI.
- Frontend optimisation via customised lazy Loading of user notifications.

JOBANPREET SINGH

UI DEVELOPER

Listening music Playing cricket Travelling Bike riding

LANGUAGES

INTERESTS

English

Hindi

Punjabi

WORK EXPERIENCE

SMART (Statistical Model Analysis and Review Tool)

This application is used by SMEs for Financial Analysis reports – BASEL and CCAR. It helps in managing the entire lifecycle for BASEL and CCAR report starting from import of files, visualisation of data and export into Word format.

Contributions:

- Frontend development using React
- Frontend optimisation via customised Lazy Loading
- Rendering NVD3 Graphs
- Production code bundling using Webpack.

System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

July 2013 - October 2016

Teacher Support Mobile App

This application is being used by most of the schools in Tamil Nadu (India). This application helps Teachers in taking attendance of the class, conducting Tests, scheduling sessions, creating curriculum etc.

Contributions:

- Frontend development using Angular
- Cache management to make app more efficient
- Database interaction
- Offline mode (it can work without internet, data will be saved locally and then get synced to database)

Game Arena

Game Arena is a platform which helps people of different ages and from different backgrounds to improve their abilities such as memorising power, visual attention, numerical skills etc. It have single and multiplayer online games.

Contributions:

- UI development/ Responsive design
- User authentication, form validations
- User communication using Sockets
- · Data transfer between client and server
- Analytics

Immersive Learning

This app helps children learn even as they interact and play with objects in the physical world. It combines physical play and virtual feedback on low-cost mobiles in powerful ways and promotes participative learning through game-play, with minimal adult supervision (or no adult supervision). A mobile device placed nearby, gently nudges the child to play-on while it discreetly measures the child's learning progress, giving subtle, real-time feedback along the way.

Contributions:

- Interaction between physical and virtual world.
- Synchronisation between local machine and cloud.
- · Usages of Image processing.
- Created a bridge between Unity and Android, so that Unity app can access all functionality that android provides.